ADITYA GOEL

ANALYTICS MANAGER / DATA SCIENTIST

(+91) 9776716083 – DTYGLL@gmail.com – Bangalore, IN linkedin.com/in/aditya-goel | github.com/adityagoel08

Associate Manager having ~5 years of experience in providing end-to-end solutions to convoluted business problems using ML models, Data analytics & Insights and Business/Product acumen.

SKILLS

Softwares: Python, SQL, PySpark, R-Studio, Teradata, Tableau, Alteryx, Salesforce, JIRA, Oracle Essbase, SAS, Jupyter Notebook, Google Colab

Machine Learning: Predictive modelling, Regression, Time Series, Forecasting, Clustering & Segmentation, Decision Trees, Random Forest, XGBoost, SVM, Hypothesis testing

WORK EXPERIENCE

Quant Modeling Associate – JP Morgan Chase, Consumer Banking (Treasury)

12/2020 - present

- Bangalore, IN
 - Area Product Owner of Mortgage Lending under Treasury, leading a team of 4 analysts in an agile environment, partnering with Business, Data and Technology teams to deliver an end-to-end price elasticity model framework which optimizes mortgage subsidies with an estd. Pre-tax NPV of \$217mm over 5 yrs
 - Conducted EDA, Feature selection and built segment level XGBoost models to predict # loans locked and pullthrough in Python
 - Predicted US Refinance market size using macro-economic indicators and mortgage associations data to help the bank in better capacity management for operations with accuracy of 87% using Polynomial regression (Python)
 - Created data pipelines and transformations from Teradata, Oracle and SQL Server to MT Discovery (Hortonworks Sandbox) using Alteryx
 - Created a daily D-o-D dashboard which shows internal mortgage rate comparisons at different levels like region,
 Fico score, etc. and a daily competitor price dashboard which shows Chase vs top 15 competitors their market shares and rates across all mortgage products (Conforming/ARMs/Jumbo/etc.)
 - Helped set and report Recruitment Strategy for Consumer Bank division to increase Diversity by 3% YTD

Pricing Analytics Associate – JP Morgan Chase, Investment Banking (Wholesale Payments) 07/2018 – 11/2020 Bangalore, IN

- Helped acquire over 50 Fortune 500 prospect clients for payment processing by participating in competitive RFP pitches using financial calculators to build pricing P&Ls, conducted stress testing and impact analysis on cards data and implemented various industry specific custom pricing strategies
- Competitor analysis on core processing thresholds, used Random Forest feature selection algorithm and developed a benchmark model for pricing strategies. Created a self-service interactive Tableau dashboard which showed competitors historical merchant pricing across verticals.
- O Developed impact analysis process in SAS for the VISA interchange updates for JP Morgan's flagship product, and later migrated the code to Python, using Numpy and Pandas amongst other packages
- o Employed SQL to wrangle, analyze, and transform financial big-data from Hive and Teradata warehouses to provide actionable insights and recommendations to senior leadership
- O Digital Platform Innovation of Payments business for RMs by transforming an excel based calculator to a webbased R Shiny application and a self-service Plug-n-Play excel model for Scenario testing
- Automated a weekly report's workflow on Alteryx to track various KPIs for the leadership team, leading to a time save of 30 odd hours per month
- Leveraged subject matter expertise of pricing and financial data to provide internal trainings, Program Manager for Community, Creative Club and Intranet Webpage across India locations

Trainee Decision Scientist – Mu Sigma, Fortune 100 Healthcare client Bangalore, IN

10/2016 - 06/2018

- Worked on Healthcare Analytics and Business Development; led a client-facing team of 3 analysts, working with the Digital CRM Campaign Management team
- Analyzed and provided recommendations for the Brand Sales team using Clustering in SAS, based on various
 KPIs of sales reps to improve their monthly effectiveness to the CRM campaign across products

- Provided insights and delivered weekly and monthly reports using sales, calls and emails clickstream bigdata for the leadership team, CRM Director and Senior Sales Executives of individual brand teams in SAS
- Developed a time-series (ARIMA) model to forecast the usage of interactive sales digital content
- o Carried out US nation-wide territory segmentation to improve sales rep training program
- Effectively drove client communications and worked on multiple client-requests (ad-hocs)

OTHER PROJECTS

- o Credit Risk modeling to find probability of default using Logistic Regression
- o K-Means and Hierarchical clustering on Consumer Credit cards to derive consumer trends
- o Multiple Linear Regression on predicting movie audience scores from critics scores
- o Time series forecasting to predict passengers on an airplane using AR, MA and ARIMA
- Customer churn for Telecom client using Logistic Regression, DT and RF Algorithms

EDUCATION

B.Tech - KIIT University, Odisha - CGPA 8.75

Graduation Year - 2016

- o President, Enactus KIIT: Created sustainable business models and led a team of 110 odd activists.
- o Intern Project Assistant in Engine shop at Maruti Suzuki India Ltd, Delhi NC
- o Intern in Coke Over section at Rourkela Steel Plant, Odisha

ACHIEVEMENTS

- 4 'Exceed Expectations' awards at JP Morgan from the Client Relationship Managers & US partners (2018,19,20)
- o 3 'Step-up awards' at JP Morgan for additional work of the CCB Intranet initiative, the Creative Club and Knowledge Management team (2018,19)
- National Finalists of the Brewmatica'19 24hour Hour Hackathon organized by AB InBev (2019)
- o President, Enactus KIIT managing a team of 110 odd activists (2016)
- AIR 10 in BAJA India All-Terrain Vehicle Competition for Vehicle designing (2015)
- o Pixel Excellence and Showcase awards for Photography (2012,13)
- o Best Team Work Apeejay Kolkata Literary Festival, Street Play (2011)

CERTIFICATIONS

- Alteryx Core Certification by Alteryx
- o Basic Statistics by University of Amsterdam, Coursera
- Understanding Financial Markets by University of Geneva, Coursera
- Financial Markets by Yale University, Coursera
- Customer Analytics by University of Pennsylvania, Coursera

ADITYA GOEL

(+91) 9776716083 / DTYGLL@gmail.com